# Rohit Nair

# Senior Full Stack Engineer

Address Mumbai, MH, 400070

Phone 814 971 2865

E-mail puthenrohit@gmail.com

Twitter https://twitter.com/rohitnairtech

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohitnairtech

WWW https://github.com/RohitNairtech

Programmer with over 6 years of successful experience in software development and deployment at scale. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to the teams success. Strengths in programming and system design. Builds simple yet elegant systems.

## **Skills**

NodeJS
Python
PHP
Vue.JS
React.JS
AngularJS
Problem resolution
API design knowledge
Project coordination
System Architure
Usability understanding
Testing and debugging
Server Architure
Natural Language Processing
Machine Learning

## **Work History**

#### 2020-01 - Current

# **Design Executive**

Insuide Technologies, Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Created and improved on system architectures
- Choosing and implementing the best approach for solving a particular problem frameworks, libraries, server architecture and communication protocols (HTTP/CoAP/MQTT/WS)
- Directed technological improvements, reducing waste and business bottlenecks.
- Shaped solutions and approaches by leveraging trends in customer marketplaces and industries.
- Supported and supervised team of 6-7 designers and developers.
- Oversaw business-wide changes to modernize procedures and organization.

# 2019-01 - 2020-01

## Senior Full Stack Engineer

Insuide Technologies, Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Worked on projects at a scale, collaborated with various teams UI/UX designers, UI developers, app developers to craft solutions.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in projects.
- $\bullet \quad \text{Engaged with UX designers to plan, optimize and fix issues and queries, on our in-app voice assistant technology.}$
- Worked on business logic in the app-side and helped UI developers create new UI components in Vue.js, React.js and Angular.
- · Worked alongside the system architect on our key products and other IPs.
- Reported directly to the CTO.

# 2018-08 - 2019-01

## **Full Stack Engineer**

Insuide Technologies, Mumbai, MH

- Single handedly completed the first NLP project under a month.
- Worked on the team assigned to create our own proprietary indoor-navigation system.
- Created APIs and collaborated with the development team.

## 2016-05 - 2018-08

# Lead Web Developer and Automation Engineer

Handloom Picture Company, Mumbai, Maharshtra

- Created their web platform and worked alongside digital marketers to improve on their SEO and site ranking.
- Worked on automating their social media handles posting, comment replies and general FAQ handling.
- Created a push notification system for their web app using service workers.
- All code was tested, perfected, and pushed to production.
- Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Generated web hosting presence to accommodate specified needs, uploading and maintaining files on account.
- Wrote lines of code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP and Python languages.

## 2014-01 - 2017-05

## XML Developer

Lionbridge Technologies, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Lionbridge is the global leader in translation and localization.
- I had the opportunity to work under different teams for a whole 2 years.

• Started as a software tester (1 month) then worked under the web development team (6 months), then under MIS excel/VBA team (1 year), later went to be a part of the rapid app prototyping team - android, web apps and desktop apps (4+ months)

#### 2014-11 - 2016-05

## MIS Developer & Data Analyst

ARPAN NGO , Mumbai, Maharashtra

- ARPAN is world's largest NGO working on the issue of Child Sexual Abuse.
- The challenge they faced was managing the large dataset that they had; their data was largely held in excel datasheets with many different formats of sheets distributed amongst different teams and employees.
- · Created scripts to consolidate data, and MIS software to mine and display data in a human readable and comparable format.
- · Using Python, PHP and VBA.

## **Education**

## 2000-01 - 2010-01 High School Diploma

Holy Family Convent High School - Vasai, Maharashtra

# 2011-01 - 2013-01 College Degree: Science Education

St. Thomas Baptista College - Vasai, Maharashtra

## 2014-01 - 2015-01 Bachelor of Science: Physics

Wilson College - Churni Rd, Mumbai

- Dropped out after a year of starting the course.
- Used that year to figure out what I want to do.

#### 2015-11 - 2018-07

## **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science And Programming**

Tilak Maharashtra Vidyapeeth - Pune, Maharashtra

- Enrolled in Bachelors after working as a software intern in Lionbridge for a month.
- In the second year worked at Arpan as a MIS developer.
- Was programming in C++, C#, ASP.net, VB.net and PHP at the time.
- · Payed the college fee on my own.
- . My last year project was awarded the 'best project of the year' worked on a time-table generator using genetic algorithm.
- Passed out with 75%.

#### 2018-08 - 2020-08

#### Master of Science: Computer Science And Programming

Tilak Maharashtra Vidyapeeth - Pune, Maharashtra

- Enrolled for Masters after securing a full-time job as a full stack developer
- Payed the college fees on my own.
- My final year project was awarded the 'best project of the year' (again) worked on Natural Language Processing Module (chatbots) implemented on Facebook Messenger without the use of a 3rd party NLP API (like dialogueflow/WIT.ai).
- Passed out with 73%.

## Certifications

2016-01

Duolingo German Fluency (Advance)

2018-11

AI For Robotics By GEORGIATECH

2018-12

NLP With Deep Learning By STANFORD

# **Additional Information**

- Black Belt in Judo
- Swam 1.5kms in 38mins
- Completed 650kms bicycle ride in 8 days
- Believe in challenging myself in all spheres of life.

## Languages

English

Malayalam Hindi

German

Marathi

# **Interests**

Slacklining

Swimming

Cycling

Body weight workouts

Meditation

## Hobbies

- Reading
- Writing down thoughts, mostly philosophical/existential.
- Philosophical pondering with the aim at better understanding life or demystifying life.

- Understanding human psyche and behavior.
- Find balance both mental and physical.
- Learning and playing musical instruments Guitar, Jew's harp and tibetan bowl.